{
  "AllQuestions": [
        {
          "Topic": "Cloud",
          "Question": "The ability for businesses to rent computing services and software from a cloud service provider on a per unit or per month basis is best encapsulated by which of the following cloud business enablers?",
          "CorrectAnswer": "Cost Flexibility",
          "OtherAnswers": [
            "Business Scalability",
            "Masked Complexity",
            "Market Adaptability"
          ]
        },
        {
          "Topic": "Cloud",
          "Question": "Collaboration software such as Zoom, Mural, and Slack are all cloud services that facilitate team communication and information sharing in real-time. This benefit of cloud is best encapsulated by which of the following cloud business enablers?",
          "OtherAnswers": [
            "Market Adaptability",
            "Masked Complexity",
            "Context-Driven Variability"
          ],
          "CorrectAnswer": "Ecosystem Connectivity"
        },
        {
          "Topic": "Cloud",
          "Question": "Company X owns and manages all its hardware and software, which are housed in an onsite Data Center. Which of the following describes the IT infrastructure that Company X employs?",
          "CorrectAnswer": "Traditional Infrastructure",
          "OtherAnswers": [
            "Public Cloud Infrastructure",
            "Private Cloud Infrastructure",
            "Hybrid Cloud Infrastructure"
          ]
        },
        {
          "Topic": "Cloud",
          "Question": "An organization using Traditional IT infrastructure may choose not to adopt a cloud deployment model for all of the following reasons EXCEPT:",
          "CorrectAnswer": "Cloud Service Providers often lock organisations into length and expensive contracts",
          "OtherAnswers": [
            "Cloud migration is seen as being too costly and time-consuming",
            "The data owned by the organisation is too sensitive to be trusted to a third-party provider",
            "The system works fine as is"
          ]
        },
        {
          "Topic": "Cloud",
          "Question": "Infrastructure as a service (IaaS) provides companies _________________.",
          "CorrectAnswer": "With computing resources including servers, networking, storage, and data center space on a pay-per-use basis",
          "OtherAnswers": [
            "Distant computers 'in the cloud' that are owned and operated by other and that connect to a users' computer via the Internet and usually a web browser",
            "A cloud-based environment with everything required to support the complete lifecycle of building and delivering web-based (cloud) applications",
            "All of the above"
          ]
        },
        {
          "Topic": "Cloud",
          "Question": "Which of the following cloud delivery models provides sophisticated security and governance designed for a company’s specific requirements?",
          "CorrectAnswer": "Private Cloud",
          "OtherAnswers": [ "Public Cloud", "Hybrid Cloud", "Edge Cloud" ]
        },
        {
          "Topic": "Cloud",
          "Question": "Acme Hospital is looking to migrate some of its workloads to the cloud. After consulting with a cloud development team, they decide on a model where general information apps will be hosted on a public cloud but sensitive data such as patient records will be stored on a private cloud. Which cloud deployment model has Acme Hospital chosen?",
          "CorrectAnswer": "Hybrid Cloud",
          "OtherAnswers": [ "Private Cloud", "Public Cloud", "Edge Cloud" ]
        },
        {
          "Topic": "Cloud",
          "Question": "Which of the following cloud service types addresses the user who does not pay for the software itself? It works like a rental. They have the authorization to use it for a period of time and pay for the software that they are using.",
          "CorrectAnswer": "Saas",
          "OtherAnswers": [ "PaaS", "IaaS", "BPaaS" ]
        },
        {
          "Topic": "Cloud",
          "Question": "_______ as a service is primarily designed for developers looking to build an application but offloads infrastructure management, patches, updates, and otheradministrative tasks to the cloud service provider.",
          "CorrectAnswer": "PaaS",
          "OtherAnswers": [ "Saas", "IaaS", "BPaaS" ]
        },
        {
          "Topic": "Data Science",
          "Question": "Which of the following is one of the most fundamental characteristics of a data scientist?",
          "CorrectAnswer": "Having a sense of curiosity about all things",
          "OtherAnswers": [ "Being proficient in R or Python", "Using open-source software libraries and packages", "Having a strong background in high power computing (HPC)" ]
        },
        {
          "Topic": "Data Science",
          "Question": "When thinking about the 5 main Vs of data, what does Veracity refer to?",
          "CorrectAnswer": "Refers to the trustworthiness of the data",
          "OtherAnswers": [ "Refers to the vast amounts of data generated every second", "Refers to the different types of data we can now use.", "Refers to the speed at which new data is generated and the speed at which data moves around" ]
        },
        {
          "Topic": "Data Science",
          "Question": "Data in all of its forms, both structured and unstructured, would be the focus of which of the following 5 V’s of data? ",
          "CorrectAnswer": "Variety",
          "OtherAnswers": [ "Volume", "Velocity", "Veracity" ]
        },
        {
          "Topic": "Data Science",
          "Question": "A data analyst is reviewing an Excel spreadsheet from an insurance company. The customer data that she is analyzing is sorted by name, home address, policy number, etc. What type of data is she most likely working with? ",
          "CorrectAnswer": "Structured data",
          "OtherAnswers": [ "Unstructured data ", "Bilaterally structured data ", "Unilaterally structured data" ]
        },
        {
          "Topic": "Data Science",
          "Question": "Which of the following tasks is a typical role of a Data Engineer?",
          "CorrectAnswer": "Statistical computing",
          "OtherAnswers": [ "Collect and clean data", "Visualizing the data", "All the above" ]
        },
        {
          "Topic": "Data Science",
          "Question": "Which of the following tasks is a typical role of a Data Analyst?",
          "CorrectAnswer": "Collect and clean data",
          "OtherAnswers": [ "Statistical computing", "Visualizing the data", "All the above" ]
        },
        {
          "Topic": "Data Science",
          "Question": "Which of the following tasks is a typical role of a Data Scientist?",
          "CorrectAnswer": "Visualizing the data",
          "OtherAnswers": [ "Collect and clean data", "Statistical computing", "All the above" ]
        },
        {
          "Topic": "Data Science",
          "Question": "Data Exploration can be best summarized as the process of ___________.",
          "CorrectAnswer": "Examining and visualizing data to find undiscovered patterns and relationships",
          "OtherAnswers": [ "Cleaning and organizing data into a usable format", "Importing data into a machine learning model", "All the above" ]
        },
        {
          "Topic": "Data Science",
          "Question": "Data Modeling can best be summarized as the process of ______________.",
          "CorrectAnswer": "Creating a visualization to communicate connections between data points and structures.",
          "OtherAnswers": [ "Cleaning and munging data into a usable format", "Examining data for hidden patterns", "All the above" ]
        },
        {
          "Topic": "Data Science",
          "Question": "_____________ is the stage whereby a data model is analyzed for its quality and efficiency in solving a problem.",
          "CorrectAnswer": "Model Implementation",
          "OtherAnswers": [ "Data Cleansing", "Data Modeling", "Model Deployment" ]
        },
        {
          "Topic": "Data Science",
          "Question": "_____________ is the stage whereby a data model is tested for its quality and put into production.",
          "CorrectAnswer": "Model Deployment",
          "OtherAnswers": [ "Data Cleansing", "Data Modeling", "Model Implementation" ]
        },
        {
          "Topic": "Security",
          "Question": "Which of the following examples best illustrates a cyber threat?",
          "CorrectAnswer": "D: Options B and C Only",
          "OtherAnswers": [ "A: A friend uses your Netflix login information without your knowledge",
          "B: You receive an email from an unknown account asking you to click on a link to claim a prize.",
          "C: Hackers infiltrate a banking website and obtain customer account information",
          "All of the Above"
        ]
        },
        {
          "Topic": "Security",
          "Question": "Based on the IBM X-Force report “The shifting panorama of global cybercrime”, what is the biggest motivation for cybercriminals to attack companies around the world?",
          "CorrectAnswer": "Espionage",
          "OtherAnswers": ["Terrorism",
          "Hacktivism",
          "Financial gain"]
        },
        {
          "Topic": "Security",
          "Question": "The use of a cyber-attack for research purposes, such as probing potential vulnerabilities within a company’s network or conducting penetration testing, is known as:",
          "CorrectAnswer": "White Hat Hacking",
          "OtherAnswers": ["Code Red Hacking",
              "Hacktivism",
              "Benign Hacking"
          ]
        },
        {
          "Topic": "Security",
          "Question": "Which of the following motivators explain why cyber criminals carry out cyber-attacks?",
          "CorrectAnswer": "E: All the above",
          "OtherAnswers": ["A: Financial Gain", "B: Hacktivism", "C: Espionage", "D: Options A and C only"]
        },
        {
          "Topic": "Security",
          "Question": "What is true about misconfiguration as one of the most challenging types of cyber threats?",
          "CorrectAnswer": "D: Options ‘A’ and ‘C’ Only",
          "OtherAnswers": ["A: Incidents where attackers gain access to vulnerable systems left exposed by inexperienced administrators or users (e.g., default factory settings)",
              "B: Employees and insiders falling for phishing emails that resulted in account takeover or access to sensitive data.",
              "C: Erroneous permission-level attribution on cloud services and networked backups exposed sensitive data through weak or non-existent authentication.",
              "E: All the above"
            ]
        },
        {
          "Topic": "Security",
          "Question": "What is the chief weapon of a cyber attacker?",
          "CorrectAnswer": "Malware",
          "OtherAnswers": ["SQLi",
          "Phishing",
          "Brute Force",
          "Physical Access"]
        },
        {
          "Topic": "Security",
          "Question": "Why are cyber-attacks significant for established companies?",
          "CorrectAnswer": "Invites regulatory penalties.",
          "OtherAnswers": ["The cost to businesses from cyber-attacks and their consequences, such as data breaches, are always affordable but exposes the company to internal inefficiencies which causes delays.",
            "Enhances the brand reputation and increases customer loyalty.",
            "All the above"
          ]
        },
        {
          "Topic": "Security",
          "Question": "Which are the five phases for the Cyber Resilience Lifecycle based in NIST CSF?",
          "CorrectAnswer": "Identify, Protect, Detect, Respond, Recover",
          "OtherAnswers": ["Investigate, Remediate, Protect, Recover, Take legal action",
          "Identify, Investigate, Remediate, Respond, Rework",
          "None of the above"]
        },
        {
          "Topic": "AI",
          "Question": "The Turing Test is designed to:",
          "CorrectAnswer": "Determine machine's human ability",
          "OtherAnswers": ["Achieve artificial general intelligence",
            "Solve the master algorithm",
            "Build machines that are aware of themselves"]
        },
        {
          "Topic": "AI",
          "Question": "The key difference between narrow intelligence and broad intelligence is best described by which of the following phrases?",
          "CorrectAnswer": "Narrow AI can only do a certain task - and it can do it quite well - but narrow AI can't transfer its knowledge to different sorts of problems as with Broad AI",
          "OtherAnswers": ["Narrow and Broad intelligence is distinguished by complexity of algorithms",
          "Broad intelligence requires huge amounts of data, whereas narrow intelligence relies on minimum data",
          "Broad intelligence can extract meaning from images, whereas Narrow intelligence is best suited for language processing"
        ]
        },
        {
          "Topic": "AI",
          "Question": "Which of the following best depict General AI?",
          "CorrectAnswer": "The ability to use previous experiences to come up with new creative ideas",
          "OtherAnswers": ["A chatbot that is also connected to Tone Analyser",
            "Watson Machine Learning service",
            "A system that is self-aware"
        ]
        },
        {
          "Topic": "AI",
          "Question": "How does IBM view the impact of artificial intelligence?",
          "CorrectAnswer": "It is here to augment human intelligence",
          "OtherAnswers": [
            "It is how systems predict the future",
            "It is about automating mundane tasks that humans do",
            "It is about the quest for artificial generel intelligence (AGI)"
          ]
        },
        {
          "Topic": "AI",
          "Question": "AI learning process entail human and machine activities; which of the following best depicts machine-related activities?",
          "CorrectAnswer": "Learns by adjusting weights and biases",
          "OtherAnswers": [
            "Identify the data-analytics problem",
            "Define hyperparameters",
            "Analyse the data provided by the model"
          ]
        },
        {
          "Topic": "AI",
          "Question": "Which of the following best describes the difference between AI, Machine Learning and Deep Learning?",
          "CorrectAnswer": "Deep Learning is a subset of Machine Learning which is a subset of AI",
          "OtherAnswers": [
            "Each level is differentiated by specific algorithms that power the system",
            "They are synonyms for the same approach for the field of artificial intelligence",
            "Machine Learning is a subset of Deep Learning which is a subset of AI"
          ]
        },
        {
          "Topic": "AI",
          "Question": "Which of the following is predominantly used with self-driving cars?",
          "CorrectAnswer": "Reinforcement Learning",
          "OtherAnswers": [
            "Supervised Learning",
            "Unsupervised Learning",
            "None, they use Broad AI"
          ]
        },
        {
          "Topic": "AI",
          "Question": "Which of the following best depict or exemplify Broad AI?",
          "CorrectAnswer": "All of the above",
          "OtherAnswers": [
            "Self-driving car, which happens to be a collection of narrow AI technologies",
            "A system that supports engineers who work on complex maintenance tasks on a platform in the Atlantic",
            "A system within a bank that analyses the balance sheet of corporate customers to recomment the best currency hedging strategy"
          ]
        },
        {
          "Topic": "AI",
          "Question": "In 2011, an IBM system won Jeopardy! - what was the underlying architecture of the system?",
          "CorrectAnswer": "It was founded on Unstructured Information Management Architecture (UIMA)",
          "OtherAnswers": [
            "It was powered by advanced neural networks",
            "It used a brute force search engine",
            "It had access to the Internet"
          ]
        }
  ],
  "ResourceLinks": [
    {
      "Topic": "Cloud",
      "Link": "https://www.ibm.com/academic/topic/cloud"
    },
    {
      "Topic": "Data Science",
      "Link": "https://www.ibm.com/academic/topic/data-science"
    }
  ]
}
